socketloop.com 2015-03-18

# Privacy Policy of Socket Loop - SocketLoop

SocketLoop.com is web site that provides tutorials and also act as a venue for technical professionals ("Users") to share knowledge and network with other technical professionals. 

Our site is committed to providing engaging, informational, and safe online environment for it's users. We are dedicated to safeguarding any personal information collected on-line and helping it's users learn how to exercise control over personal information while exploring the Internet. We take special measures to protect their privacy while on-line. For example, we do not ask to disclose more personal information than is necessary for them to participate in a particular activity, and we take extra effort to prevent users from posting contact information.

To help ensure a rewarding on-line experience for our visitors we provide you with this summary of our information practices.

As we continue to offer our visitors new and different types of content and services, we may modify our practices from time to time. However, we will treat all personal information we collect in accordance with the privacy notice in effect at the time the information is collected.

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**  
When visitors come to the site, we automatically collect some non-personally identifiable "computer" information, such as the type of computer operating system , the web browser being used, and information regarding the Internet service provider. 

For added functionality, the site requires that users provide essential information such as a email address and unique site identification to create member accounts.

**USE OF INFORMATION**  
We use visitors' personal information only for our internal purposes of enabling visitors gaining access to additional site features such as to subscribe to our online newsletter, or to inform users of upcoming events and special announcements. We use the names and e-mail addresses of subscribers to our e-mail newsletter only to send them the newsletter. Each newsletter contains instructions on how to be removed from the subscription list by sending us a return e-mail.

We sometimes use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of the site, to personalize our visitors' experience on the site, and to offer products, programs, and services. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze site usage, as well as to offer products, programs, or services.

We will disclose information we maintain when required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency's request.

We will not use or transfer personally identifiable information in ways that are materially different from the ones described above without also providing parental notification of such practices and obtaining consent for any materially different uses.

**INFORMATION COLLECTED BY THIRD-PARTY SITES AND ADVERTISERS**  
This site contains links to other sites, including those of advertisers, whose information practices may be different from ours. Visitors should consult the other sites' privacy notices, since those sites are not covered by our privacy policy and may follow procedures that are different from ours. This site never gives a user's e-mail address to advertisers without permission, however, if you choose to "opt-in" (click on a box to receive an advertiser's information), to register with one of our advertisers, or not to "opt-out" (uncheck a checked box that will provide an advertiser with your information), that means you have allowed this site to give your e-mail address to that advertiser.

**COOKIES**  
This site uses a software technology called "cookies." Cookies are small text files that we place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. Cookies themselves do not contain any personally identifiable information. Although cookies could enable us to relate a visitor's use of this Web site to personal information that a visitor has provided, such as an e-mail address, we do not use them for this purpose. We do use "cookies" to determine how many visitors we have and how often they visit various sections of the site.

**CONTACT US**  
If you have any questions, comments, or concerns regarding our privacy policy and/or practices, please contact us at admin@socketloop.com .

**THIRD PARTY COOKIES**  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser.
